Kyle Goetke

101 Overhill Rd, Summit, NJ 07901 home (908) 464-2566 cell (908) 499-8047 goetkek@protonmail.com

Profile

Motivated high school student with background knowledge in IT services and computer hardware, leadership experience, and strong problem-solving and interpersonal skills. Experience working with enterprise-level hardware in professional environments.

Technical Skills

Languages: Python, HTML, JavaScript, Java, SQL

Certifications: IC3 Digital Literacy, Microsoft Office Specialist, CompTIA IT

Fundamentals, Oracle Database Foundations

Additional Experience: Windows, Ubuntu Linux, building computers, team programming,

pair programming

Education

Union County Academy for Information Technology

2016 - Present, will graduate in June 2020

- Completed AP Computer Science Principles and am enrolled in AP Computer Science A
- Served as a club officer in the AIT Coding Club
- Currently serve as Chair of the Hardware Committee in the AIT Coding Club
- Served as AIT Class Historian
- Academic Honor Roll: 2016 2019

Work Experience

Union County Vocational-Technical Schools / IT Intern

2019 - Present

- Assist school faculty with resolving technology issues.
- Responsible for maintaining existing technology.
- Organized and set up new hardware for incoming students.

New Providence School District / Technology Assistant

2016 - 2018

- Responsible for sorting and installing new hardware and software.
- Assisted with organizing old hardware and software.
- Cooperated with team members to integrate new and old technology.

Other Experience

Appalachia Service Project / Volunteer

2017 & 2019

- Helped repair homes and improve living conditions for low-income families.
- Cooperated with others to achieve a goal in a limited time frame.
- Worked with limited supplies to achieve the best outcome.

New Providence High School Marching Band / Percussion

2016 - Present

- Played auxiliary percussion and currently play the marching bass drum.
- Participated in winter Indoor Drumline.
- Serve on the band's senior leadership council.

Boy Scouts of America / Eagle Scout

2013 - Present

- Held several positions of responsibility including Senior Patrol Leader and Junior Assistant Scoutmaster.
- Fostered development of new skills in younger scouts

Personal Projects

Python Programs - Created programs for fun and to assist with schoolwork

- Molar mass calculator (for Chemistry)
- Kinematic equation solver (for Physics)
- Tip calculator (calculates various tip amounts for restaurant meals)

Bash Scripts - Created scripts to automate tasks

- Enabling low-power mode on a laptop
- Updating the system and programs
- Displaying system information (temperature, resources, etc.)

Digital Portfolio - Digital collection of achievements and skills

- Created using self-taught knowledge of HTML and CSS
- Hosted on GitHub Pages